FREDERICK CHEN

FULLSTACK WEB3 DEVELOPER

WWW.CHENFREDERICK.COM



ABOUT ME

Professional solution-driven fullstack web3 developer with around 5 years of experience specialize in frontend development.

Experienced on building websites along the stages of web development cycle (web2 & web3), meeting highest standards of best practices, and a lifelong learner.



CONTACT

Fmail:

me@chenfrederick.com

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/frederick-chen

Github:

https://github.com/frederick-88

Website:

www.chenfrederick.com



EDUCATION

Universitas internasional Batam

Bachelor of Information System 2019 - 2023 GPA: 3.88

Glints Academy - Impact Byte

Fullstack Javascript Bootcamp 2020



SKILLS

Technologies: Vue.js (Vue2 & Vue3), Nuxt.js (Nuxt2 & Nuxt3), React.js, Web Performance, SEO, Vuex/Redux/Pinia, Web3, Viem, Ethers.js, Hardhat, Smart Contract (Solidity), Alchemy, Ganache, Unit Testing (Jest/Mocha-Chai), Git/Github/Bitbucket, Wordpress (CMS), Vuetify/Bootstrap/Tailwind.css, MYSQL/MongoDB, Laravel, ExpressJS/Node.js, AWS, Cloudflare, Nginx/Apache, Firebase, GSAP, Browserstack, Storybook, Linux, Scrum.

Program Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS/SCSS, Solidity, Typescript, PHP, SQL.



EXPERIENCES

IMAGINARY ONES - EULI STACK WER3 DEVELOPER

02/2023 - CURRENT

Websites Contributed:

a. www.imaginaryones.com & other sub-websites/projects (over 1.1M twitter followers)

Main Contributions:

- Develop UIs and systems/features for various projects of a well-known NFT Brand with Vue3, Nuxt3, Web3 and the ecosystem, ensure animated & seamless user interactions.
- Contribute to various Web3 system developments, e.g NFT/Token Staking, HugoBlue Web3 Purchase with USDT, TGE \$BUBBLE Token Claim, etc.
- Collaborate with backend developers, designers, and product managers to deliver high-quality solutions based on project requirements, while also use Clickup, etc.
- Ensure quality SEO settings and optimal web performance.
- Contribute to design, development, unit-test, deployment and implementation of smart contracts (solidity), leveraging blockchain for secure & transparent transactions.
- Implementing scalable, clean & readable code habit with Big-O, GetBEM, KISS, DRY, etc principles.
- Perform frontend unit testings with minimum coverage of 85% with Jest and Vue-Test-Utils.
- etc

OFFEO - FRONTEND DEVELOPER

08/2020 - 12/2023

Work on Both OFFEO & Imaginary Ones Under the Same CEO since February 2023. Websites Contributed :

a. www.offeo.com & the other sub-websites/projects

(over 300k users & million visits of monthly traffic)

Main Contributions:

- Develop UIs & systems/features of a seamless + interactive image/video editor tool (similar to Canva) with Vue2, Vue3, Nuxt2, Nuxt3, and the ecosystem, via Figma.
- Integrate API from backend to exchange data within database.
- Ensure quality SEO settings and optimal web performance.
- Reduced bugs backlog by around 95% monitored with clickup across OFFEO sites.
- Perform unit testings with minimum coverage of 85% across OFFEO & IO sites with Jest and Vue-Test-Utils.
- Reviewing pull requests (PR) + deployments to Staging & other website stages.
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Leveraging Browserstack for Cross-Browser front-end development}.$
- · Contributed to system that crafts & runs animation on website with GSAP.
- Implementing scalable, clean & readable code habit with Big-O, GetBEM, KISS, DRY, etc principles.
- Contributed to docs of OFFEO's component-library with Storybook (like Bootstrap).
- Develop internal websites (e.g admin site, designer site, etc), where 1 of them via Fullstack Development with (Inertia+Vue+Laravel+MySQL).
- Work together along with other developers with Bitbucket + Github version control.
- etc.

GLINTS - WEB DEVELOPMENT INSTRUCTOR

10/2020 - 12/2021

Main Contributions:

- Share knowledge & best practices in web development.
- Create + manage javascript assessment & live code questions for students.
- Teach solutions for every live code questions as simple as possible to students.
- Train web developers students from glints academy bootcamp.
- etc.

FREDERICK CHEN

FULLSTACK WEB3 DEVELOPER

WWW.CHENFREDERICK.COM



CERTIFICATES

OFFICIAL TOEIC TEST - 890/1000

https://bit.ly/toeic-frederick

HACKERRANK - JAVASCRIPT

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/6769fc4d31ea

HACKERRANK - CSS

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/a635abd049c8

DATA STRUCTURES & ALGORITHMS

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/ UC-6e21f4be-f9f1-4100-a2ff-cbc4a1d8910a/

FULLSTACK JAVASCRIPT DEV BOOTCAMP

https://network.impactbyte.com/certificate/frederick-chen

see all 10+ certificates in LinkedIn



SELECTED PROJECTS

ASIA PROPERTY

· www.asiaproperty.netlify.app

Beautiful & modern real estate website that is developed with full-stack development (React.js, Redux & Express.js) from first designing phase until last deployment phase based on ideas received from themeforest.com & dribbble.com, styled purely with CSS.

GLOBALUI COMPONENTS LIBRARY

• https://global-ui-docs.netlify.app/ & https://www.npmjs.com/package/global-ui

A UI Components Library that is created with Vue.js, so i created the base and setups for each component, then later on developers can just simply import and use it (similar to bootstrap, materialUI, vuetify, etc). Support the usage for Vue.js or Nuxt.js developers. A system example for agencies that want to have consistent UI. Also have UI documentation created with Storybook.js. Deployed as a NPM package to be an opensource package installable for any developers around the world.

AWS TUTORIALS

https://www.youtube.com/@frederick88/videos

Created Youtube Videos about AWS Deployments and Uses - With Lots of Tech Stack Inside (Vue, Nuxt, React, Express, S3, RDS, Security Group, Elastic IP, MySQL, etc)

PERSONAL WEB (CHENFREDERICK.COM)

• www.chenfrederick.com or https://staging.chenfrederick.com

Amazing responsive personal website with dark mode feature & web animations. Accessible within any device and screen from 320px to larger than 2560px. Sharing more about my capabilities, experience & skills. This web has staging site and live site system. VIsit this personal web to see the other 20+ amazing portfolios!